Capital Defender Office; Records apap309
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- Murder Two Indictments, 1995-2007; 4; 2.4 cubic ft.
  - Schuyler County Murder Indictments, 2002 (Box 3 (4-Murder Two Indictments), Folder 5)
  - Suffolk County Murder Indictments, 1996-2003 (Box 3 (4-Murder Two Indictments), Folder 6)
  - Sullivan County Murder Indictments, 1997-1999 (Box 3 (4-Murder Two Indictments), Folder 7)
  - Tomphins County Murder Indictments, 1996 (Box 3 (4-Murder Two Indictments), Folder 8)
  - Ulster County Murder Indictments, 1995-1999 (Box 3 (4-Murder Two Indictments), Folder 9)
  - Wayne County Murder Indictments, 1999 (Box 3 (4-Murder Two Indictments), Folder 10)
  - Westchester County Murder Indictments, 1996-2005 (Box 3 (4-Murder Two Indictments), Folder 11)
  - Wyoming County Murder Indictments, 1997-2001 (Box 3 (4-Murder Two Indictments), Folder 12)
- Subject Files, 1975-2007; 5; 3 cubic ft.
  The subject files series contains correspondence, verdict sheets, publications, annual reports, and research on capital punishment.
  - Al-Salahi, Ala Muslim, 2001 June (Box 1 (5-Subject Files), Folder 1)
  - AI State Meeting at UVA, 2005 February 26 (Box 1 (5-Subject Files), Folder 2)
  - Arlington Co. Fair Booth-AI/VADP, 2003-2007 (Box 1 (5-Subject Files), Folder 3)
  - Articles in which Any of the Following People Discuss the Death Penalty: Dennis Vacco, James Catterson, Jeanine Pirro, William Fitzpatrick, Undated (Box 1 (5-Subject Files), Folder 4)
  - Articles in which Ay of the Following People Discuss the Death Penalty: Howard Relin, Michael Green, Richard Brown, Michael Kavanagh, and Frank Phillips, Undated (Box 1 (5-Subject Files), Folder 5)
  - Baiza, Transito, 1992 September 10 (Box 1 (5-Subject Files), Folder 6)
  - Barber, D'Alesandro, 1993 September-October (Box 1 (5-Subject Files), Folder 7)
  - Barnabei, Derek, 2000 September (Box 1 (5-Subject Files), Folder 8)
  - Beavers, Thomas, 1992 July 8 (Box 1 (5-Subject Files), Folder 9)
  - Boggs, Richard, 1990 August 19 (Box 1 (5-Subject Files), Folder 10)
  - Bramblett, Earl, 2000 December 5 (Box 1 (5-Subject Files), Folder 11)
  - Breard, Angel Francis, 1998 (Box 1 (5-Subject Files), Folder 12)
  - Briley, Linwood, 1984 (Box 1 (5-Subject Files), Folder 13)
  - Buchanon, Douglas M., 1995 February 16; 1997 April 9 (Box 1 (5-Subject Files), Folder 14)
  - Bullock, James, 2004 July 24 (Box 1 (5-Subject Files), Folder 15)
  - Bunch, Timothy, 1992 (Box 1 (5-Subject Files), Folder 16)
  - Catholics and the Death Penalty Bishop Sullivan and Delegates, 2005 September 17 (Box 1 (5-Subject Files), Folder 17)
  - Catholics Teaching and Relics of American DP, 2006 March 25 (Box 1 (5-Subject Files), Folder 18)
  - Capital Defender Office Second Annual Report, 1997 October (Box 1 (5-Subject Files), Folder 19)
  - Charbrol, Andrew, 1992 May 20; 1993 June 17 (Box 1 (5-Subject Files), Folder 20)
  - Chichester, Carl Hamilton, 1993 September (Box 1 (5-Subject Files), Folder 21)
  - Charles, Clay, 1991 October 22 (Box 1 (5-Subject Files), Folder 22)
  - Churches- Invite to Join VADP, 2005 February 23 (Box 1 (5-Subject Files), Folder 23)
  - Clanton, Earl, 1984-1988 (Box 1 (5-Subject Files), Folder 24)
  - Clark, James T., 1985 June 24 (Box 1 (5-Subject Files), Folder 25)
  - Clozza, Albert J., 1991 July (Box 1 (5-Subject Files), Folder 26)
  - Coleman, Roger, 1983-1985 (Box 1 (5-Subject Files), Folder 27)
  - Coppola, Frank, 1982 (Box 1 (5-Subject Files), Folder 28)
  - Correll, Walter, 1995 February 18 (Box 1 (5-Subject Files), Folder 29)
  - Couric Civic Adovcacy Award- Rosenfield, 2004 (Box 1 (5-Subject Files), Folder 30)
  - Davidson, Mickey, 1993 January 5 (Box 1 (5-Subject Files), Folder 31)
  - "Death- Defying Feats: State Constitutional Challenges to New York's Death Penalty" Mary R. Falk and Eve Cary, 1995 (Box 1 (5-Subject Files), Folder 32)
  - Death Penalty New Conference, 2001 January 16 (Box 1 (5-Subject Files), Folder 33)
  - Death Penalty Outlines, 2002 (Box 1 (5-Subject Files), Folder 34)
  - Death Penalty Research, Undated (Box 1 (5-Subject Files), Folder 35)
  - Delong, Wayne Kenneth, 1993 June; Undated (Box 1 (5-Subject Files), Folder 36)
  - Eaton, Dennis, 1998 (Box 1 (5-Subject Files), Folder 37)
  - Edmonds, Dana Ray, 1984; 1992 (Box 1 (5-Subject Files), Folder 38)
  - EPB MTD Group Project, 2005 August (Box 1 (5-Subject Files), Folder 39)
  - Equal Justice Report, 2006 October 10 (Box 1 (5-Subject Files), Folder 40)
  - EJ and EP Media Advisory, 2006 October 11 (Box 1 (5-Subject Files), Folder 41)
  - EJ and FP Press Conference Agenda, 2006 October 12 (Box 1 (5-Subject Files), Folder 42)
  - EJ and FP VADP Statement, 2006 October (Box 1 (5-Subject Files), Folder 43)
  - Evans, Willbert, 1990 (Box 1 (5-Subject Files), Folder 44)
  - Fahey, Helen, 1993 June 10 (Box 1 (5-Subject Files), Folder 45)
  - Federal Execution Procedure, 1993 January 19 (Box 1 (5-Subject Files), Folder 46)
  - Fincham, James, 1993 September 7 (Box 1 (5-Subject Files), Folder 47)
  - Fisher, David Lee, 1995 February 17 (Box 1 (5-Subject Files), Folder 48)
  - Fitzgerald, Edward, 1984; 1992 (Box 1 (5-Subject Files), Folder 49)
  - Fry, Tony, 1995 March 29 (Box 1 (5-Subject Files), Folder 50)
  - Garioni, Mitchell, 1991-1993 (Box 1 (5-Subject Files), Folder 51)
  - GAO Report "Death Penalty Sentencing Research Indicates Pattern of Racial Disparities", 1990 February (Box 1 (5-Subject Files), Folder 52)
  - George, Michael Carl, 1997 (Box 1 (5-Subject Files), Folder 53)
  - Governor Ryan to Speak of UVA- VADP Events 2005, 2005 January 21 (Box 1 (5-Subject Files), Folder 54)
  - Gray, Coleman, 1986 December 23; 1995 March 5 (Box 1 (5-Subject Files), Folder 55)
  - Harris, Darrel Amicus Brief, CANY Draft Part 1, 2000 December 1 (Box 1 (5-Subject Files), Folder 56)
  - Haysom, Elizabeth, 1987-1988 (Box 1 (5-Subject Files), Folder 57)
  - Herndon Friends Meeting, 2005 November 5 (Box 1 (5-Subject Files), Folder 58)
  - Hines, Alfred Howard, 1987 February 18 (Box 1 (5-Subject Files), Folder 59)
  - Hoke- Petersburg, VA, 1991 October; 1995 February 15 (Box 1 (5-Subject Files), Folder 60)
  - Hudson, Henry E., 1985 November 22; 1989 March 28 (Box 1 (5-Subject Files), Folder 61)
  - Johnson, Harold Anthony, 1992 October 28 (Box 1 (5-Subject Files), Folder 62)
  - Jones, Willie, 1992; Undated (Box 1 (5-Subject Files), Folder 63)
  - Judge Kloch, John E., 1997 February 13 (Box 1 (5-Subject Files), Folder 64)
  - Journey of Hope- Potluck, 2004 April 23 (Box 1 (5-Subject Files), Folder 65)
  - Justus, Buddy, 1990 December 13 (Box 1 (5-Subject Files), Folder 66)
  - Juvenile D.P. Panel Event, 2004 October 5 (Box 1 (5-Subject Files), Folder 67)
  - Kansi, Mir Animal, 1997; Undated (Box 1 (5-Subject Files), Folder 68)
  - Kidd, Jah-Lil A., 1993 (Box 1 (5-Subject Files), Folder 69)
  - King, Becky, 1991 March 14; 1992 November (Box 1 (5-Subject Files), Folder 70)
  - King Book Talk, 2005 April 1-3 (Box 1 (5-Subject Files), Folder 71)
  - Ksepka, Jennifer, 1992 June 17; 1992 August 9 (Box 1 (5-Subject Files), Folder 72)
  - Legal Aid Party, 2005 April 7 (Box 1 (5-Subject Files), Folder 73)
  - Leuasseur, John Joseph, 1982 September 4; 1984 September 20 (Box 2 (5-Subject Files), Folder 74)
  - Mackall, Tony, 1987 October; 1992 September 16-17 (Box 2 (5-Subject Files), Folder 1)
  - Mackey, Philip English "Hanging in the Balance", 1982 (Box 2 (5-Subject Files), Folder 2)
  - Marrot, Angel Jean, 1991 (Box 2 (5-Subject Files), Folder 3)
  - Mason, Morris, 1984 November 14; 1985 January 11 (Box 2 (5-Subject Files), Folder 4)
  - Meeting with Bob Blue Warner, 2005 March 9 (Box 2 (5-Subject Files), Folder 5)
  - Mickens, Walter Jr., 2001 (Box 2 (5-Subject Files), Folder 6)
  - Mini Journey of Hope, 2004 April 23 (Box 2 (5-Subject Files), Folder 7)
  - Montane, Rolando Respondent's Brief, 1975 (Box 2 (5-Subject Files), Folder 8)
  - Mueller, Everett, 1991-1992 (Box 2 (5-Subject Files), Folder 9)
  - Mu'min, Dawud, 1992 (Box 2 (5-Subject Files), Folder 10)
  - Murphy, Mario, 1993 September; 1997 September 18 (Box 2 (5-Subject Files), Folder 11)
  - Muwwakkil, Kamal S., 1993 (Box 2 (5-Subject Files), Folder 12)
  - NCADP- Council of Affiliates 2004 Year in Review, Undated (Box 2 (5-Subject Files), Folder 13)
  - Nationwide Capital Statues [1 of 2], ca. 1998 (Box 2 (5-Subject Files), Folder 14-15)
  - New Jersey Death Penalty Commision Study Report, 2007 January (Box 2 (5-Subject Files), Folder 16)
  - New York State Assembly Death Penalty Debate [1 of 3], 1995 March 6 (Box 2 (5-Subject Files), Folder 17-19)
  - News Conference, 1999 March (Box 2 (5-Subject Files), Folder 20)
  - NLG Talks, 2004 March 1 (Box 2 (5-Subject Files), Folder 21)
  - Novak, Shawn Paul, 1991; 1992 (Box 2 (5-Subject Files), Folder 22)
  - Oakton Church of the Brethren, 2006 February 5 (Box 2 (5-Subject Files), Folder 23)
  - O'Dell, Joseph Roger, 1987-1988 (Box 2 (5-Subject Files), Folder 24)
  - Payne, Joseph P. Sr., 1988-1998 (Box 2 (5-Subject Files), Folder 25)
  - Peterson, Derick, 1991 August (Box 2 (5-Subject Files), Folder 26)
  - Pope, Carlton, 1995 June 17 (Box 2 (5-Subject Files), Folder 27)
  - Police Shootings, 1989-1991 (Box 2 (5-Subject Files), Folder 28)
  - Possible Event- Photo Diary, Undated (Box 2 (5-Subject Files), Folder 29)
  - Possible Radio Spot, 2005 March 11 (Box 2 (5-Subject Files), Folder 30)
  - Poyner, Syvasky, 1993 (Box 2 (5-Subject Files), Folder 31)
  - Pruett, David Mark, 1993 (Box 2 (5-Subject Files), Folder 32)
  - Quintana, Manuel, 1983 (Box 2 (5-Subject Files), Folder 33)
  - Radcliff, Robin, 1993 February 17 (Box 2 (5-Subject Files), Folder 34)
  - Ramdass, Lee, 1992; 1993 (Box 2 (5-Subject Files), Folder 35)
  - Rambert, Arthur, 1993 April 18; 1993 September 7 (Box 2 (5-Subject Files), Folder 36)
  - Reed, Thomas, 1991 (Box 2 (5-Subject Files), Folder 37)
  - Report of the Governor's Commission on Capital Punishment- George H. Ryan, Governor, 2002 April 15 (Box 2 (5-Subject Files), Folder 38)
  - Robinson, George Alec, 1986 March 8 (Box 2 (5-Subject Files), Folder 39)
  - Roanoke College, 2004 February 26 (Box 2 (5-Subject Files), Folder 40)
  - Rosenfield Reception, 2005 March 10 (Box 2 (5-Subject Files), Folder 41)
  - SALT, 2005 September 17 (Box 2 (5-Subject Files), Folder 42)
  - Satcher, Michael Charles, 1991 (Box 2 (5-Subject Files), Folder 43)
  - Savino, Joseph John, 1995 (Box 2 (5-Subject Files), Folder 44)
  - Shambaugh, Ralph, 1993 (Box 2 (5-Subject Files), Folder 45)
  - Sheppard, Mark, 1995 May 1 (Box 2 (5-Subject Files), Folder 46)
  - Sing Sing Death House Case Files 0135-80, Undated (Box 3 (5-Subject Files), Folder 1)
  - Smith, Ray Bruce, 1989; 1997 (Box 3 (5-Subject Files), Folder 2)
  - Spenser, Timothy Wilson, 1994 (Box 3 (5-Subject Files), Folder 3)
  - Stamper, Charles, 1993 (Box 3 (5-Subject Files), Folder 4)
  - Starkey, James Robert, 1992 (Box 3 (5-Subject Files), Folder 5)
  - Stockton, Dennis, 1995 (Box 3 (5-Subject Files), Folder 6)
  - State of New York Temporary Commision on Revision of the Penal Law and Criminal Code- Special Report on Capital Punishment, Undated (Box 3 (5-Subject Files), Folder 7)
  - Talk at VCU, 2005 April 19 (Box 3 (5-Subject Files), Folder 8)
  - Taylor, John Brief Amicus Curiae, 2006 November 8 (Box 3 (5-Subject Files), Folder 9)
  - Thomas, Chris, 1992 (Box 3 (5-Subject Files), Folder 10)
  - Townes, Richard "Foot Ball" Jr., 1987 February 23; 1987 April 1 (Box 3 (5-Subject Files), Folder 11)
  - Tuckahoe Presbyterian Church- Alan Gell, 2006 January 22 (Box 3 (5-Subject Files), Folder 12)
  - Tuggle, Lem, 1996 (Box 3 (5-Subject Files), Folder 13)
  - Turner, Willie, 1982 (Box 3 (5-Subject Files), Folder 14)
  - UU Church of Charlotteville JPT Talk, 2006 May 7 (Box 3 (5-Subject Files), Folder 15)
  - University of Richmond School of Law- "Is There Life For the Juvenile Death Penalty After Malvo?", 2004 February 19 (Box 3 (5-Subject Files), Folder 16)
  - Values and the Death Penalty, 2005 (Box 3 (5-Subject Files), Folder 17)
  - Vasquez, David, 1988-1989 (Box 3 (5-Subject Files), Folder 18)
  - Verdict Sheets [ 1 of 2], Undated (Box 3 (5-Subject Files), Folder 19-20)
  - VA Film Festival, 2005 October 26-29 (Box 3 (5-Subject Files), Folder 21)
  - VA Elections, 2005 November 8 (Box 3 (5-Subject Files), Folder 22)
  - VA People of Faith, Undated (Box 3 (5-Subject Files), Folder 23)
  - VA POF, 2003-2004 (Box 3 (5-Subject Files), Folder 24)
  - VA POF, 2000-2001 (Box 3 (5-Subject Files), Folder 25)
  - VA POF, 1999-2000 (Box 3 (5-Subject Files), Folder 26)
  - VA People of Faith, 1998-1999 (Box 3 (5-Subject Files), Folder 27)
  - VA POF Moratorium Samples, 2000 October; 2002 September (Box 3 (5-Subject Files), Folder 28)
  - VPOF Signatures on Mission Statement, 1999 March 5 (Box 3 (5-Subject Files), Folder 29)
  - VADP Death Row Support Project, 2004 May (Box 3 (5-Subject Files), Folder 30)
  - VADP Flyer "Not One More. Nunca Mas.", Undated (Box 3 (5-Subject Files), Folder 31)
  - VADP Lobbying, 2006 February 13 (Box 3 (5-Subject Files), Folder 32)
  - VADP Media Release, 2004 May 28 (Box 3 (5-Subject Files), Folder 33)
  - VADP Members' Registration Forms, 2005 December 15 (Box 3 (5-Subject Files), Folder 34)
  - VADP Member- Nottingham, Mason, 2005 August 2 (Box 3 (5-Subject Files), Folder 35)
  - VADP- Nova Chapter, 2005 November 10 (Box 3 (5-Subject Files), Folder 36)
  - VADP Project Ideas, 2006 February 26 (Box 3 (5-Subject Files), Folder 37)
  - VADP Possible Event-DP Play, 2005 February 26 (Box 3 (5-Subject Files), Folder 38)
  - Virginia's C.U.R.E, 2004 September 18 (Box 3 (5-Subject Files), Folder 39)
  - VADP's Conference 2004, 2004 September 30 (Box 3 (5-Subject Files), Folder 40)
  - VADP Projects 2005, 2005 March 8 (Box 3 (5-Subject Files), Folder 41)
  - VADP Event- Lisa Thomas Walk Rt. 29, 2005 April-May (Box 3 (5-Subject Files), Folder 42)
  - VADP Press Conference on Simmons, 2005 March 1 (Box 3 (5-Subject Files), Folder 43)
  - VA General Assembly-Senator Couric, Emily, 1997 July 17 (Box 3 (5-Subject Files), Folder 44)
  - Washington, Earl Jr., 1993 (Box 3 (5-Subject Files), Folder 45)
  - Watkins, Johnny Jr., 1994 (Box 3 (5-Subject Files), Folder 46)
  - Waye, Alton, 1983 January 25; 1984 August 7 (Box 3 (5-Subject Files), Folder 47)
  - Weeka, Lonnie, 1993 (Box 3 (5-Subject Files), Folder 48)
  - Weston, Frank, 1985 (Box 3 (5-Subject Files), Folder 49)
  - White, Curtis, 1992 June (Box 3 (5-Subject Files), Folder 50)
  - Whitley, Richard, 1987 July 7 (Box 3 (5-Subject Files), Folder 51)
  - William and Mary- Journey of Hope, 2004 April 22 (Box 3 (5-Subject Files), Folder 52)
  - Williams, Stan "Tookie" VADP Sponsored Benefit, 2005 December (Box 3 (5-Subject Files), Folder 53)
  - Williams, Terry, 1999 April 9 (Box 3 (5-Subject Files), Folder 54)
  - Willis, Kiree Tige, 1993 September 7-9 (Box 3 (5-Subject Files), Folder 55)
  - Wise, Joe Louis, 1993 (Box 3 (5-Subject Files), Folder 56)
  - Wilson, Kenneth, 1995 April 2 (Box 3 (5-Subject Files), Folder 57)
  - Wright, Dwayne Allen, 1994 (Box 3 (5-Subject Files), Folder 58)
  - Yeatts, Ronnie, 1995 December 14 (Box 3 (5-Subject Files), Folder 59)
  - Zirkle, Daniel Lee, 2002 April 3 (Box 3 (5-Subject Files), Folder 60)
  - 38/50 Capital Embroidery Exhibit, 2005 July (Box 3 (5-Subject Files), Folder 61)
- News Clippings, 1993-2007; 6; 70 cubic ft.
  Chronological.
  The news clippings cover the death penalty in New York State from 1995-2007. The material is arranged by year, there are a set of originals and a set of duplicates of the same clippings. The materials are housed in the original manner that they were donated in from the New York Capital Defender Office.